Alexei Rusu | Full Stack Software Engineer

Saratoga Springs, NY | (518)-915-5569 | <u>rusualexei1995@gmail.com</u> | <u>/in/alexei-rusu-dev/</u> | github.com/Alex-dev7/

| portfolio- work in progress

As a full-stack web developer with a background in choreography, I bring a unique perspective to the development process. My combination of technical expertise and creative vision, honed by my choreographic education, allows me to approach problem-solving and design from a holistic perspective.

Skills

Languages - JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Python. Libraries and Frameworks - React, NextJS, Express.js, jQuery, Bootstrap, Tailwind, Django, FastAPI, Flask. Databases - MongoDB, Mongoose, Cloudinary, SQL, PostgreSQL. Other - Node.js, RESTful Routing JSON, MVC, TypeScript, Figma, SCRUM

Software Development Projects

09/2022- PRESENT

SupplySmart - React.js, Django, Python, PostgreSQL, Cloudinary, SASS: Live | GitHub-frontend | GitHub-backend

- Served the back-end of the application using Django and Python methods and functions utilizing PostgreSQL database management.
- Integrated Cloudinary API in the backend, to handle image upload and save the URL in my PostgreSQL database, therefore allowing users, to upload an image along with the item's description.

MyEvents - React.js, Node.js, Express.js, SASS, Bootstrap, MongoDB, Mongoose, CORS: <u>Live | GitHub-frontend | GitHub-backend</u>

- Build a decoupled app with a separate server and front-end, which results in better scalability and maintenance of the application.
- Collaborated with three other developers to create a MERN Stack application, in one week with full CRUD operations hitting all RESTful API calls, and testing all routes during development using Postman.
- Wireframed and planned the UI design of the application with Figma, and implemented it using SASS and Bootstrap.

Missing Pets - Express.js, EJS, MongoDB, Mongoose, JavaScript, Node.js, Bcrypt: Live | GitHub

- Used Mongoose to define schemas for MongoDB collections.
- Implemented user sign-in, profile creation, and social features using Session Based Auth, Bcrypt, and MongoDB for secure authentication and database management.
- Server-rendered web app using Express and EJS, written in a modular format for easy maintenance in the future.

Pocket-Sommelier - AJAX, JavaScript, API, CSS, HTML: Live | GitHub

- Styled app according to stakeholder requirements incorporating jQuery to manipulate the DOM, HTML, and CSS to render a responsive, appealing, and accessible user experience.
- Built a responsive frontend by integrating CSS flexbox and grid, ensuring user best practices were met across mobile and desktop devices.
- Integrated an API using AJAX to retrieve and populate the UI with dynamic data, allowing for real-time updates and improved user experience.

Professional Experience

07/2022-08/2022

Lake House Bistro | Freelance-Web Developer | Lake George, NY | lakehousebistro.com

- Built a static website for a local restaurant, using Vanilla JavaScript, HTML5, and CSS3 in order to make it responsive, and user-friendly.
- Created a form page, and connected the HTML to a form-managing endpoint, to allow potential employees to submit a job application.
- Ongoing development: refactoring the entire site to React.js, and integrating it with a content management system (CMS).

Northern Hospitality Management | Maintenance Specialist | Lake George, NY

10/2020-PRESEN

- Utilized complex problem-solving skills to respond to emergency situations efficiently, maximizing guest satisfaction and minimizing disruption to resort operations, resulting in a 90% satisfaction rate from guests.
- Led and completed renovations and resolved problems involving electrical and mechanical engineering, plumbing, and carpentry, resulting in a 40% reduction in maintenance-related work orders.

Fred Astaire Dance Studios | Choreographer and Dance Teacher | Saratoga Springs, NY

04/2019-10/2020

- Choreographed over 50 groups and partnered dances for students of all ages and experience levels, to be performed at professional events.
- Invested extra effort into upskilling and mastering The Fred Astaire official curriculum in order to prepare for examinations, certifications, and promotions.

Choreographer and Dancer | The SPACE Project | Chisinau, Moldova

09/2016-01/2019

• Managed the marketing and hiring of dancers through direct client engagement and advertising, resulting in a 30% increase in client satisfaction and a 20% increase in dancer retention.

• Created and choreographed 15 stage performances for television, music videos, and other events and projects, resulting in an increase in viewership and engagement.

EDUCATION

General Assembly | Remote

04/2023

Software Engineering Immersive | Full-stack software engineering immersive student in an intensive, 450+ hour program focused on product development fundamentals, object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and team collaboration strategies. Developed a portfolio of individual and group projects.

Academy of Music, Theatre and Fine Arts | Chisinau, Moldova